# Nicholas Patten

Flat 4, 18 Blackall Road, Exeter, Devon, United Kingdom, EX4 4HE 07790200756, nicholaspatten92@gmail.com

### **Profile**

Dev-Ops engineer with over two years of experience in the software industry. Capable of working as part of a team, or independently to fulfill the role. Willing to learn from, and teach others in order to improve delivery of the product.

# **Experience**

- Languages:

Groovy (Gradle & Jenkins DSL), Java, Javascript, Bash, C

- Frameworks:

Grails, Ruby on Rails, Spring

- Database & Database Related:

Oracle, SQL, Hibernate, JPA, Data-Modeling

- Build Automation & Continuous Integration:

Maven, Gradle, Jenkins, Artifactory

- Development & Testing Tools:

JUnit, Powermockito, archaius, Tomcat

- IDE's & Text Editors:

Eclipse/STS, NetBeans, Atom, Kate, VIM

- Version Control:

Git, Mercurial

- Markup, Stylesheet and Template Engines:

XHTML, JSON, CSS, XML, Freemarker, LATEX

- OS.

Windows, Mac OSX, Various Linux distributions e.g. Debian, CentOS/Redhat, CoreOs

# **Employment**

#### **Present**

### 2014 - 17 CMS Release Manager, Mirada Exeter

Responsible for the managerial and development aspects of providing releases of the company's CMS product to various environments to support business continuity.

The management side of this role involves communicating with other teams to ensure that their schedules are on time for the next release and working to resolve any blockers that they may encounter.

The development side of this role focuses on designing build processes. This is often programmatically declared using languages such as groovy and bash, which are normally accompanied by Jenkins' jobs. Maintenance and improvement of these processes and scripts are core to the continuous delivery of the product.

Operational tasks are occasionally required as issues arise in deployment environments, which need to be taken care of before the install process can continue.

#### **Past**

#### 2013 - 13 National Museum, Cardiff

Short period of work experience, assisting a senior network supervisor. Various skills gained, including managing network cables, cabinets and HP server blades.

# 2011 - 11 Oxfam, Cardiff

Charity work as a shop floor assistant and stock organiser. Gained team working skills and customer service experience.

# 2008 - 08 Maplin's Electronics, Cardiff

Work experience as a shop floor assistant. Gained high-quality team working and customer service skills.

# Education

# 2011 - 14 Aberystwyth University; Computer Science BSc Hons:

Major Project; Ms. Pac-Man Artificial Intelligence Software Controller:

Researched and developed an autonomous software controller for the Ms Pac-Man game, based around the goal of maximising the score the controller could achieve.

### Modules:

C++, C And Java Programming Paradigms

C And Unix Programming

Concepts in Programming

Agile Methodologies

Software Development Life-cycle

**Developing Internet Based Applications** 

Modelling Persistent Data

**Computing Mathematics** 

### 2009 - 10 St David's Catholic College; GCE A Level:

Computing, Film Studies, Welsh Baccalaureate

### 2004 - 09 St Teilo's CIW High School; GCSEs:

Nine GCSE's, including: IT (A), DT: Systems and Control (B), English Lang & Lit (C), Maths (C), Science (C)

### **Interests**

Keen interest in the development of hardware and software. Enjoy debating the future of the computing industry with other like minded people. Maintain my own self-built desktop, water-cooled gaming PC. Planning to develop many more personal projects. Avid video game enthusiast, across multiple platforms.

Intrigued by the hardware behind various systems, particularly the constantly expanding choice of work/ entertainment environments and the way the industry will learn to adapt to changing times. Enjoy socialising, going to the cinema, keeping fit by swimming and in the past have trained in the martial art of Karate.

#### Referees

References available on request